The difference is four points.
COMMENTARY MORITAKA SUWA
Lord Tokiyuki needs five more points
to make a comeback!
IRKED
What is that about?
He's absolutely going to try
to stop him from scoring.
ONE POINT - THREE POINTS
He only has two arrows left.
He has to hit a head or a neck to win.
Give up.
It's impossible for you to make
a four-point comeback at this point!
-My lord!
-Young Lord!
Well, I think we've got a winner.
Run, Chojumaru!
You think you could be a match
for Sadamune
just with your shooting abilities?
You must combine evading and shooting!
I have to evade while I shoot?
Lord Yorishige, do you think
he understood what you meant?
It's all so clear.
When I start running,
my head clears, and I can see everything.
If I aim for a dog, Sadamune will run
into me from my blind spot for certain.
It's impossible for me
to hit a small moving target
while trying to ward off his attacks.
Wait, I know!
There's one target I can aim for
in a split second.
A reverse shot. You're aiming behind you?
You idiot.
It's called a blind spot because I'm in
a position where you can't shoot me.
You can't twist your body any further
while you're mounted on that horse.
I am elusive
and the heir to the Hojo clan.
TWO POINTS
While I'm running away, I can do anything!
Reverse shot on the opponent's neck.
Two points!
SUWA 3 - OGASAWARA 5
DOG-SHOOTING COMPETITION 1333
-You did it!
-Yes!
I get it!
COMMENTARY MORITAKA SUWA
If my lord aims for a dog, Sadamune
is sure to come from his blind spot.
The angle and distance
are much more certain,
and he's a much larger target than a dog!
That split-second judgment.
His sense of balance and flexible body
make acrobatic marksmanship possible.
That boy's potential blooms
when he's on the run.
It's decided.
Our lord's special move is a reverse shot.
In the future, there'll be a word that
makes a youngster's heart leap for joy.
-What?
It's not over yet!
It's still five to three.
Here comes a right-handed shot.
As long as I cover my head,
he can't make a comeback!
A classic example
of attacking while running away.
It's called…
PARTHIAN SHOT
The Parthian shot.
Parthia was an ancient kingdom
in the Middle East.
They used this backward-facing tactic
to defeat Rome,
the strongest army
in the world at the time.
As the enemy got near,
the Parthians attacked while they ran.
They continued to fight
with hit-and-run tactics.
The Roman army's heavy infantry, having
no way to retaliate, ran out of energy.
Reverse shot on the opponent's head.
Three points!
Right on!
SUWA 6 - OGASAWARA 5
With a score of six versus five,
Chojumaru wins!
-Yes!
-You did it!
Take that, punk! Go, Chojumaru!
That's for shooting the shrine maiden.
It was just a coincidence
I hit his ear, though.
Congratulations on your victory.
YORISHIGE APPEARED!
Isn't it fun to fight while running away?
TOKIYUKI - FIGHT - RUN
We can continue
to come up with more and more ways!
Now, Sadamune,
it's time to fulfill your promise.
Leave Suwa
and don't meddle with us ever again.
Don't be so full of yourself.
A dog-shooting competition
is just for entertainment.
You sided with traitors so your territory
should immediately be forfeit!
I'll look thoroughly
for the Hojo survivors afterwards!
HERE
Damn Yorishige.
Why did you bring out the kid?
It's hard to believe
he had a sure chance of victory.
And his mannerisms and behavior…
He had the bearing of a nobleman
you don't usually see at his age.
Could he be part of the Hojo family?
No, Yorishige wouldn't bring forward such
an important person right in front of me!
I don't understand
Yorishige's intentions at all!
Sadamune has good eyes.
He should be baffled
because he noticed too much.
We have arranged with a certain individual
to spread rumors of
the Hojo clan sightings all across Japan.
Gods and people exist
only if you have faith.
Simply believing in them gives them power.
With suspicions abound
all throughout the country,
our enemy's attention will be divided.
May you grow strong.
This is a battle you advance
while running.
You're already running on the journey
to win back the country!
THE ELUSIVE
SAMURAI
"A useless and dishonorable skill
for a warrior."
That's what they said
about the skills I've learned for my lord.
The better I got at it,
the more trust I lost.
The lord to whom I was long devoted
accused me of stealing from him.
And I was banished.
Listen. You are my successor.
In my final hours, you will inherit
my name and my principles.
Trust only money.
Neither trust nor devotion will return
once you've lent them out.
Use your skills
and trust only money, Genba!
You can do it, my lord.
One, two. One, two. One, two.
Good work. A little more!
Why does the heir to the shogunate
have to perform such physical labor?
Right now,
you're Suwa Grand Shrine's Chojumaru.
Enemies coming to visit will be suspicious
if we don't have you working already.
The only enemy who would come is Sadamune.
But he suffered huge embarrassment
just yesterday,
so he probably won't
show his face for a while.
Hi!
-What?
He's here with a smile.
What a resilient man.
I've kept you waiting, Suwa folk.
I bring an Imperial Command.
An Imperial Command?
Didn't he bring one last time?
COMMENTARY MORITAKA SUWA
The Imperial Command from the other day
was appointing Sadamune as governor.
Today's Command is probably…
"You are traitors
who have sided with Hojo.
As punishment,
the Suwa clan and their retainers
must forfeit the lands
north of Lake Suwa to Ogasawara."
FORFEITURE
You're lying.
Within ten days, retainers living in
the corresponding regions must relocate.
Deliver the news with dignity
like a good lord.
What should we do?
We've cultivated this land tirelessly
since our ancestor's time!
We can't just hand it over
to that Sadamune creep without a struggle.
That's right!
We must go to war.
Lord Yorishige, please command us.
If we go against the Imperial Command
and go to war,
we'll become an enemy of the court.
Now is not the time to rise up.
That's enough for today.
Everyone, you're free to go.
-Chojumaru.
-Yes.
Stay behind. I have a task for you.
What?
I see you've named yourselves
the Elusive Warriors.
It's a good name. It suits you.
I don't feel like that's a compliment.
Anyways, what are you going to do?
At this rate, the people of Suwa…
You understand reason
and have a sense of justice.
But having those two qualities
is not enough.
In fact, there's someone I want to recruit
to the Elusive Warriors.
What?
He's a thief named Genba Kazama.
A thief?
He uses all sorts of trickery.
He can also get in anywhere
and steal anything.
Wow!
But,
why do we want a thief in our company?
There's something I want to ask of you.
Have him go into Sadamune's residence
and steal the Emperor's Imperial Command.
According to information from Kyo,
it's taking quite some time
to issue Imperial Commands.
If this one goes missing,
it'll buy us a good amount of time.
END OF THE LINE
This is so wrong.
Yes. But in the world we're joining,
you'll need more than righteousness
to bring forth justice.
You shall learn to make use
of wicked people as retainers too.
You'll be prepared as a general
with everything in your arsenal.
Are you sure, Lord Yorishige?
Letting the children
and Lord Tokiyuki go by themselves?
He's a child, but he is a ruler's child.
You are sure to see
he is fit to be a lord.
KIKYOGAHARA
He should be in this village somewhere.
Excuse me.
Yes?
May I ask a question?
What is it, you beautiful, young ladies?
We're looking for someone.
Oh, I see. Do you know their name?
Yes. Genba Kazama.
Genba Kazama.
…is his name.
How bad do they hate him?
It's loud and clear
they want nothing to do with him.
No one dares to get on my bad side.
If someone makes an enemy of me,
they're sure to see hell.
He's in the tree!
For some reason,
our lord is also in the tree!
My name is Genba Kazama.
I heard my name from
about ten kilometers away, so I've come.
State your business.
I'm Chojumaru of Suwa Grand Shrine.
I wanted to personally add you
as my retainer.
What do you mean, "Chojumaru"?
You're Hojo's brat, aren't you?
I wonder how much you'd go for
if I sold you to Sadamune.
Young Lord, get away!
Damn it. I knew we couldn't trust a thief.
Don't be in a hurry, you idiots.
Negotiations are just beginning.
-My wallet!
TO BE BIG IS A GOOD THING
What skill!
My skill isn't cheap.
I want 100 kanmon
for not ratting you out to Sadamune.
100 KANMON = FIVE MILLION YEN
100 kanmon for each job I perform!
That's so expensive!
Money?
I won't let you get away with even
a single mon's worth of discount.
If you want my help, money is the thing
that'll tie us together.
Money.
If he's shocked at this point,
we're not getting anywhere.
If you don't have money, you can't
get anyone to do anything for you.
I don't care how royal
the house you came from is.
Right now, you're just a brat
who can't do anything.
You're not fit to be a lord.
This is reality, brat!
So, I just have to pay you?
Yes.
If you can!
Are you planning on taking out a loan?
Are you sure that's enough?
You don't want a province?
What?
-A province?
-To be honest, I was surprised.
If you become my retainer
and help me recapture the country
with your incredible talent,
you'd be an original distinguished vassal
from the start of the war.
KAI - MUSASHI
It would be a no-brainer to give you
a province, like Kai or Musashi.
How unselfish you are.
You ask not for a province,
but only for money!
Kai? Musashi?
I'm shocked.
Slowly. There we go.
I would be confused too.
The Suwa Grand Shrine will guarantee
payment for your daily expenses.
But are you sure cash is really okay?
Once Big Brother takes the country
and gives you a province,
you'll gain tens of thousands of kanmon.
E-V-E-R-Y year.
I get it, I get it.
This really is a gamble.
Take a small amount now
or bet on future returns
by serving my lord.
But,
you won't bet on this dream of a gamble?
The ruler's child
helplessly coming to you for a favor
will only happen once in a lifetime.
Stop whispering in both of my ears!
Let me decide for myself!
Damn it. I was thinking of fooling them
and swindling some money.
But, it's fine.
This might stain.
Hey, brat.
You said you wanted me to steal
the Emperor's Imperial Command.
I have one condition.
OGASAWARA'S RESIDENCE
The Emperor's Imperial Command
was very effective.
I'll chip away at Suwa's territories,
and soon it'll all be mine!
I'm not planning on risking my life
for an irresponsible employer.
I'll take the job
only if you're willing to come with me.
The Imperial Command is in that warehouse.
Just as the shrine maiden said.
I thought you'd be too scared to come.
Of course I'll come with you.
I was the one that was told to go steal
the Imperial Command.
Oh, you are so admirable.
But be careful.
If we mess up, we'll end up like them.
THE THIEVES
Can we trust him?
What if he takes our lord to a place
he can't escape and sells him out?
It's going to be okay.
Lord Yorishige is the one
who recommended him.
We, too, simply became
the Young Lord's retainers one day.
And it's been fun, right?
Well, that's true.
I don't tire of that lord.
KING
Three tightly secured locks.
Can you open it?
That's nothing.
The problem is the two guards
in front of the warehouse.
In the end, people are the best locks.
But my special skill
is getting through those locks.
Follow me if you've got the guts.
BOUNCE
He's so excited.
Are you the type to do
whatever someone tells you to do?
You're the child of a high-ranking
warrior. Do you not have any shame?
A warrior's shame?
I threw most of that away
when I ran from Kamakura.
And I'm not doing this
just because I was told to.
I want to repay my debt
to the people of Suwa.
If I can repay the people
who warmly took me in,
I don't see that as a disgrace.
That's stupid.
Listen, birdbrain.
Exchanges through obligations or honor
will eventually lead to loss.
If you can't physically see it,
it might as well not exist.
But offer money or instill fear,
and you can get people to do anything.
Money or fear?
For example, there was a woman
who refused to pay me after the fact
for investigating her husband's affair.
So I snuck into her house.
I put roaches and pee in some rice.
And I cooked it up
nice and fluffy for her.
Ever since then,
no one's dared to snub me.
Oh, I see why no one likes him.
People only believe in what they can see.
Genba?
Don't move.
Hey.
Sadamune?
I can't be here.
But where should I go?
Plus, Genba told me not to move.
Genba?
What if he planned
to lure me here to begin with.
Sir!
The nails
on the warehouse's northern end are loose.
Go fix it immediately.
But we've been commanded
to not leave the warehouse.
You idiots!
What if the enemy attacks tonight?
Will you atone for your mistakes
with your heads?
I wasn't thinking. I'll fix it right away!
Sir. By the way,
why do you have those ears?
I want people to think I'm cute!
Did it work?
Yes!
It snuck up on me like a night ambush,
but it's right up my alley!
KING
This mask
is made of secret ancestral clay.
I can morph into most people.
Did he know who I was
because he'd morphed into someone I know
and snuck into Suwa Grand Shrine?
I know
you thought I deceived you just then.
Is this what
the Imperial Command looks like?
Genba?
Someone who can steal anything,
morph into anyone.
Anyone would distrust
a subordinate like that.
Can you trust me enough to hire me?
Young Lord, you were already betrayed
by a million soldiers.
I hear something in the warehouse.
Whispers. Two male kids?
What happened to the guards?
They're at the northern wall?
Why would they be there?
-Goro.
-Sir!
Go wake Sadamune.
Hikohachiro, go wake the retainers.
Setaro, go communicate with the gate.
Sir!
If they hadn't put me in here
on this moonless night,
I wouldn't have had to
cut some rascals' throats.
Translated by Emily Walton
EPISODE 6 (YEAR OF 1333):
STEAL THE IMPERIAL COMMAND FROM
OGASAWARA'S RESIDENCE AT NIGHT
Let's go!